Misery loves company.
Thir13en Ghosts is a horror, thriller film directed by Steve Beck.
Arthur and his two children inherit his uncle's estate: a glass
house that serves as a prison to twelve ghosts.
When the family, accompanied by a nanny and an attorney, enter the house they find themselves trapped
inside an evil machine 'designed by the Devil and powered by the dead' to open the Eye of Hell.
Aided by a ghost hunter and his rival, a ghost rights activist out to set the ghosts
free, the group must do what they can to get out of the house alive.
Arthur, played by Tony Shalhoub.
Kalina, played by Embeth Davidtz.
Rafkin, played by Matthew Lillard.
Kathy, played by Shannon Elizabeth.
Bobby, played by Alec Roberts.
Ben Moss, played by JR Bourne.
Thirteen Ghosts (also known as 13 Ghosts and stylized as THIR13EN Ghosts) is a 2001
supernatural horror film directed by Steve Beck in his directorial debut.
A remake of the 1960 film 13 Ghosts by William Castle, the film stars Tony Shalhoub, Embeth
Davidtz, Matthew Lillard, Shannon Elizabeth, Alec Roberts, Rah Digga, and F.
Murray Abraham.
The film was considered a box-office disappointment,
grossing $68 million on a $42 million budget.
Thirteen Ghosts received generally negative reviews from
critics, though the production design was praised.
Years after its release, the film garnered a cult following.
In 2023, Dark Castle Entertainment announced a television adaptation.
The film explores themes of sacrifice, self sacrifice,
single parent, chase, supernatural.
The tone is dark and intense.